you don't have them actually write a
prompt because frankly they're not good
at writing prompts that's part of the
problem you just have them click a
button to run a prompt that someone else
in their team made to generate a great
unit test or something like that then
they're like holy [ __ ] this actually
worked pretty well and then they can go
see what's the kind of prompt that I had
to write and so often when we would find
people saying hey this stuff didn't work
well we'd say what prompt are you using
and there they' go boneless again but
once we got find out what the prompt
they were using it was obvious
you're listening to the AI native Dev
brought to you by
[Music]
Tesla hi welcome to the AI native Dev
podcast I'm really excited today to uh
be chatting with a fantastic guest Quinn
slack from Source graph I'm Dion alir I
work at tessel now and excited to be
chatting with you on the podcast Quinn
welcome would you like to introduce
yourself yeah thank you Dion I'm happy
to be here and talk about code Ai and
agents and all of that I'm Quinn I'm the
C co-founder at source graph and been a
developer all my life I've felt what
it's like to work on massive projects
and code got some patches to curl curl
dhel you'll see one of the flags I added
sent patches to open SSL and G TLS and
all that and that was these formative
days in in as a coder where I got to
feel what it was like to work at a
massive codebase and try to understand
the damn thing and it's hard that was
before AI yeah that's awesome so let's
go back a bit in time just to get a bit
of a ground in so Source graph like we
know of Cody now on the AI side but it
it started with code search I I think
inspired by Google's internal grock
system and the like can you talk about
the early years a little bit and uh and
talk about the code search side of
things and the problems you were solving
there and still do yeah seeing those
pains in working these big code bases
that's why we started Source graph and
now we've got amazing customers we have
every Dev at stripe and Uber and four of
the six top US Banks using us and so on
but back when we formed Source graph it
was because we had felt that pain it's
hard to code and it's way more
repetitive than it should be we felt
that pain ourselves my co-founder felt
that pain at Google and together we felt
that pain inside two big US Banks where
we're working inside and writing code so
we wanted to go and solve that we wanted
to accelerate human developers and if
you go back to our seed deck step two is
we want to go automate software
development and there is no technology
available to really do that in the way
that would be magical back when we
started Source graph but we knew that if
we could build code search that would do
two things it would immediately make it
so that human developers fa with this
massive problem the biggest problem in
software development trying to
understand the damn thing would be able
to do so better and it would also
prepare and and groom and till the
fields of the codebase so that when
there was some magical brain that could
ingest all the code and do amazing
things with it then all the code would
be in one place we'd have something that
all the devs in a company were using so
it felt like a necessary step and it
just so turned out that code search it
was not just a good first step it was
also something really valuable by itself
and so that's what we built we built
that and the coolest moment that I
remember in the first two weeks after
started Source graph is we were building
Source graph and we had this way for you
to see where everybody else is calling
this function in the open source world
and I was writing some code and I said
oh I'm G to use Source graph and see if
someone's already done this thing and
there was some other go package that
somebody had written that did exactly
what was going to take me the next two
weeks so two weeks into building it it
had already saved me two weeks it was
like a perpetual motion machine it was
pretty amazing that's awesome so I
worked at Google and got to use the gro
system there so I super excited because
I think a lot of Google Engineers when
they would leave like they missed
certain tools that they didn't have
access to anymore and so it was awesome
to get access to some of those tools
thanks to yourselves at source graph so
was awesome to see then fast forward in
a little bit when the whole gen space
blew up again with BT if you can think
back to then uh I'm curious what your
initial reactions were like were you
skep skeptical at first when did you
know that potentially change and then
what happened to trigger you like really
investing and jumping into something big
with building out Cody so the summer
before chaty BT we were working with
anthropic and we had access to Claude
which was amazing it was in our source
graft slack and we had access to the API
and we found that hey this can do
amazing things this can actually explain
code not just autocomplete which was the
only code AI functionality that was
available at the time it could fix code
it could generate unit tests it could
generate whole files of code and
obviously it's gotten a lot better in
the two and a half years since then but
that was amazing and we knew that was
the future we knew that what we were so
well positioned given that we had all
these big customers using us for code
search we had all their code they were
already trying to solve a lot of the
same problems hey how does this damn
thing work and they use code search for
it and wouldn't it be amazing if we
could also give them AI for it so when
chat gbd came out we said oh yeah this
is like Claude that we have and this is
really cool and I even remember I would
show my parents and my family like hey
look it can create song lyrics and
everyone around us thought oh chat
that's nothing new but of course it was
and that was a huge moment in the
industry and I think looking back at
that time
it's like a bcad moment we obviously put
a lot more investment into our AI since
then and we've come a long way and still
literally every week every other week
our customers are doing something with
it that is just surprising and new and
it's never stopped being so exciting
feels like people are working at 300%
ever since chbd came out and I
absolutely love it that's awesome that's
so funny that you got to see it the
other way around being early on the
anthropic side whereas I think most
people it was chat GPT was their first
kind of view into that moment that's fun
especially now given how fantastic that
Claude Sonet is at writing code all of
the Improvement since then that's really
fun that you had an extra early kind of
seat at the table to watch this happen
so I'm really curious about the
underlying technology and Concepts that
you had with code search and how that
maps to kind of modern rag because I see
time and time again the kind of same old
stick with retrieval where it's just
like easily chunking up a document doing
some coign similarity and there we go
we've done retrieval but code isn't just
text in a document or anything like that
so like how do you see his code being
different than text for the use case of
actually like really doing a good job of
retrieval and how to code search I'm
assuming here like help there yeah it's
such an interesting topic there's three
groups of people here there's the
academic Ivory Tower people there's the
Enterprise Ivory Tower people and then
there's the people who actually use the
damn thing and rag was a term we were
doing it and I was meeting with some
more academic people and they're like
what do you think of rag I'm like what
are you talking about like retrieval
augment of generation I'm like what and
I'm like Oh you mean using search to
find code and then present and they're
like yeah that's Rag and I looked and
there's all these academics who were
doing stuff and just so funny that there
was such a divide there and now it feels
any kind of rag approach most of the
industry never actually did it that well
99% of rag implementations never did any
chunking or never measured in a rigorous
way and that's absolutely crazy we do a
lot of rigorous measurement of it and
now it's already past the point where
rag is sufficient now most context
fetching is done with some agentic you
can say like rag gentic to figure out is
the first fetch sufficient what other
terms might you need to explore what
other tools you need to use to pull in
context so I think it's already Way
Beyond Rag and the challenge is to be
really rigorous about for what use cases
is this kind of context fetching good
but really it's a black box of a lot of
different techniques the code search
that we built before all the AI stuff
came out that was incredibly valuable
just having a code index and all the
repos was incredibly valuable but we've
had to add in in a lot of new ways to do
retrieval and indexing and it turns out
that virtually all of those things
they're also useful for humans just
doing code search we found ourselves
like how we hoped it would work out in a
really good position where code search
is a great foundation for any AI system
that you build on top yeah that's
awesome so could you walk us through a
little bit of like the evolution of Cody
from the beginning from co- completions
instructions now hear a lot about chat
oriented programming and what were the
kind of like the insights along the way
as you went through that Journey yeah we
started out with the chat that was the
first way that you could use cod and
that was to fix code to understand code
then we built autocomplete we built
edits and basically it was a new tool
that was out there we were the first to
come out with the code chat that at the
time really everyone was using
autocomplete and you've got a few kind
of competing features in AI you
obviously have the autocomplete I think
everyone uses that you have chat with
chat there's a lot of different ways
that can be exposed and I I'll talk
about some of the things that we do
differently that make sense for the
Enterprise versus for the individual
then there's edits where you select some
code and you do option K and you say oh
go and do this that became really
popular now autoedits is valuable I'm
coding a ton on a little side project
over the last few weeks in the holidays
and I think about 50% of the code that I
wrote was from our Auto edits which is
where it's like autocomplete but it can
go and suggest edits elsewhere in the
file too you have all these features at
a at a feature level and if you're an
individual Dev that's just doing stuff
that you can figure out and and maybe
consistency and quality is not the most
important thing you're just trying to
move fast but we are totally focused on
the Enterprise and I think the
Enterprise is the most interesting place
to be building code AI because they have
a massive code base and they do things
where you have a thousand uh times per
day that they're generating a unit test
and they have the kind of scale that you
can actually automate and that is
calling for a completely different kind
of code AI product than what you'd make
if you're just trying to make someone
who's building an app from scratch or
who's working on a kind of low stakes
personal project really fast and I love
the Enterprise because it's where all
the real software gets built all the
best devs work at the Enterprise all the
best software is built in the Enterprise
and if you disagree with that I would
just say hey if a Dev is so damn good
they're going to build such good
software that their company becomes so
successful
that in a few years it's going to be an
Enterprise so the Enterprise is where it
all happens and there's so much more
potential to make code AI great in the
Enterprise than what you can do for the
individual yeah that makes sense it does
I don't know about you it drives me a
little nuts at times to see the kind of
Twitter Echo chamber of look at this AI
generating a little sample app from
scratch which is it's a use case it's
good for prototyping and all of those
kind of things but to your Point that's
just very different than the 99% case of
you're already in existing codebase and
in the Enterprise is probably massive
and maybe you're in a very large monor
repo maybe they've got lots of different
repos how do you make sure your best
practices working be between these
different worlds The onboarding
Experience like one of the yeah most fun
things that I saw talking to a customer
of of Orman in the past was just this
new employee and she just joined and
she's got a little bit of impostor
syndrome right doesn't know the team yet
and is able to use chat like like you're
talking about with Cody to just get this
understanding of the code base and like
it just the amount of just trust we able
to get from the system and it's
obviously there 247 it's not oh man my
TL is time zones away and they're not
available right now it just utterly
changed on boarding experience which
again these Enterprises have a few
developers in there right so being able
to help with those kind of use cases
that's gold right yeah like yeah the
quick demos aren't really often
showcasing those type of features there
are other things that you've seen in the
Enterprise from customers that are just
like actually like this is where they're
getting a lot of value and it's not just
the autocomplete this bit of code yeah
we like to look for areas where if you
step back you think first principles hey
it's crazy how everyone's doing this and
the rag situation was one where everyone
was talking about rag but basically
nobody was actually chunking in a
thoughtful way no one was measuring how
good their chunking is no one was
measuring the effectiveness or accuracy
of their Pipeline and for a lot of the
companies that were they had a separate
academic team that had a bunch of
techniques but none of them were
actually getting in in production so it
it's like measurement but it was totally
pointless and one big area we saw that
was like the emperor has no clothes with
Cod AI in the Enterprise was was the way
that developers were using chat across
an Enterprise they were all basically
this was a year ago chicken typing
prompts ad hoc on their own each time
and so if two developers wanted to go
make a test or wanted to go add a new UI
screen they would go and they would type
type and this developer would do it
differently from this developer and this
developer and there's no sharing of the
prompts and what a wonder that it
actually worked our context fetching is
pretty damn good we'd find some files
but hey obvious opportunity to make it
so that if two developers are doing the
same thing in an Enterprise use the same
damn prompt and one of our customers
stripe has an internal chat tool that's
for general purpose chat and they have
talked publicly about this prompt
library that they built internally so
that Stripes could share prompts for
writing a good documentation or a good
public summary or that straight
marketing fi they do such a good job
with their marketing and hey why don't
we make that for
our Ai and we have a prompt library that
means that if two developers are
generating unit test or making a new UI
screen or any of these kinds of things
they're going to use the same damn
prompt and if a senior Dev wants to make
sure that everyone on my team who's
doing this thing they do it really well
they can go and and make that prompt
really good and they can edit it if it's
needs to account for something else that
is such a basic fundamental thing is so
obvious The Prompt is such an important
part of the input you get to the AI and
it was crazy to me that still even now
that we've had this out there for more
than six months and in massive use by
our Enterprise customers that no other
code tools have it we have customers
where they're driving more than 80% of
their chat usage through prompt library
and that's amazing because the quality
is better the consistency is better and
think of all the time save from
developers not chicken typing their
little prompts on their own so that's
like just one of many examples of where
in the Enterprise you can do that
because by the way you cannot do that if
you're building an AI tool for
individuals because an individual is not
going to put in 20 minutes up front to
sit down write a great prompt for doing
something that they only do once a month
they're not going to do that but in an
Enterprise it's someone's job to do that
it's the tech lead or the manager's job
to do that and there's an incentive to
put in time upfront because it's
advertised over all the times that it's
used so I love the Enterprise yeah
that's awesome yeah you think about
being like that someone who's a
principal engineer of a large company
and they're really struggling with how
to spend their time right they want to
help as many people on the team as they
can but they've got a bunch of code that
they need to write as well and so like
where do they put their time and so
being able to go in there and be like
virtually on the shoulder of all of the
engineers helping out not in a creepy
way like that impact is just massive
right it's being able to like you say I
that across is just absolutely huge and
so all of the value that gets put into
the system being able to spread that
across the team I think as a game
changer and yeah the other thing that
I'm super excited about within the
Enterprise 2 and I'm curious if you've
seen this at all is I saw some companies
that totally changed the structure of
their engineering teams where they they
could go back to having smaller teams
with these tools and with maybe
utilizing another core team that's
setting up some of those pieces in
particular domains and then they can
move fast again because they're back to
being a small team without all of the
coordination cost and so they can do so
much more in in totally I think that
point about how it changes how a senior
developer Tech lead has influence over
the team is really interesting I hadn't
thought of this but it's almost like
they're shifting left their work where
instead of waiting until code review
which is like post micromanagement which
is the most annoying kind of
micromanagement it's yeah not only are
these a bunch of annoying comments but I
wish you had told me before I wrote the
whole damn rest of the pr now they can
actually influence how the code is being
written and one next step that we're
taking is making it so that every line
of code written will run through the
standards that have been set for the
code base so we get that feedback
instantly it's not just being used when
you're generating new code but it's also
being used for all the code that you're
writing as a human I think that's going
to be a much better kind of mode than
waiting for a senior engineer to review
something and you got to wait on that
because I think in code riew every
single code riew comment should be is a
failure it's not that Cod is bad you
should do it but it's a failure that
that failure is maybe a mean term but
think of it like a factory every time
there's a defect in a product in a
widget made on the conveyor belt it's
not saying someone [ __ ] up it's saying
that's a failure in our process so every
code riew comment it's a failure that
the person writing that code did not
know that they should have done it
somehow different it's not their fault
but the system has to think how can we
make it so they would not have made that
mistake in the future and that's how you
could move so much faster you can get
these dumb repetitive facts out of the
human brain and make it so they can
think about the higher level things so
we want to eliminate code riew comments
not by saying let's throw out code rview
obviously has a purpose but how do we
make it so it's not as necessary and
that is a really exciting Frontier that
a lot of our customers are pushing on oh
that's awesome yeah another area that I
saw I'm curious if this resonates too is
just like there's all of these areas
that are really painful like
accessibility is an example I've never
seen a company that has invests enough
in accessibility it's always a really
maybe it's a really small core team of
expertise maybe it's just like a few
people on the team that kind of know it
right and I was talking to one company
where there's one engineer that's just
really passionate about testability and
has a lot of expertise and he was just
like hey in code review time because it
hasn't happened earlier one in 10
reviews I'll be on and so basically that
means one in 10 PRS good accessibility
right whereas being able to put that
into the system and having that as part
of the best practices for accessibility
itself just eliminates that entire
problem and then you have performance
security all of these like horizontal
kind of crosscutting concerns that a lot
of abds maybe don't have the full
expertise you can't expect everyone to
have that level of it right you now can
have this ability where you can have the
abds run to your point really fast but
you've got the kind of guard in place by
giving the experts in the company the
ability to have that influence earlier
on exactly and that's such a shift from
someone who's really passionate about
accessibility thinking that we need to
educate every single human Dev on how to
do that well versus how can they make it
so that the system has high
accessibility I think there's a bit of a
moral veillance here yes it's good for
every developer to know and care about
accessibility on a personal level my mom
went blind in the last five years and so
I've gotten to see how she uses her
devices and it's incredible Apple does
amazing things with accessibility and
I've seen also like cookie banners make
websites so hard to navigate this is
personal for me and I've been using uh
Source graph AI when I'm coding to
understand like for me it was a lot of
basic stuff how to do Arya and how to do
roles on elements and I didn't know that
I've got some prompts and some
techniques that help me but the moral
veilance here I think is important we
have to change the idea of what it means
to be a software developer it's actually
a virtue to not need to know all the
low-level stuff and we've accepted this
with so many other Evolutions in the
role where you're not writing assembly
code you don't know a lot of the
fundamentals hell most programmers don't
know how to do some basic CS
fundamentals and look we've gotten there
as an industry so you got to eliminate
the moral veillance and it's okay if
developers don't know all about security
or performance the reality is they don't
know that today but you think that it
should be their job instead let's figure
out how do we make it so the system has
great accessibility great security great
performance and how can AI sitting on
the shoulder developers actually help
there and again that's only possible in
the Enterprise because those things
security performance accessibility means
something different based on the
codebase the stack the product you're
working on the business requirements and
you're only going to take the time
upfront to figure out how can we make a
system that enforces those things well
in an Enterprise yeah that makes sense
have you seen anything around helping
with dependency management migrations
every Enterprise I've been in is they're
always working on projects to migrate
from here to here which seems like a lot
of a waste of time from like the
business value side of things but it's
really important to stay up to date and
so I think that could be an area too
where AI could just like massively help
just with these massive large code bases
a lot of it is Legacy stuff how do you
change that whole system and just like
you're saying with like code review
getting earlier what if the world is
constantly updating and staying up to
dat and so you don't get into the
situation of needing a project Phoenix
to rebuild everything from scratch do
you see that at all yeah this comes up a
ton every Enterprise has dozens or maybe
hundreds of code migrations they want to
be doing and most of them are not
getting done some of them are and this
is also where we've seen customers start
to build agents on Source craft to go
and automate some of these we had this
event in December of
2024 where a bunch of our customers
talked about the agents that they built
on Source craft palalo Network has built
a code of view agent booking has built a
bunch of code migration agents and these
are in those cases for booking these are
oneoff agents that they use for big
migration like a monor repo to
microservices migration for this part of
the code and we've seen incredible
results from these kinds of AI driven
migrations but the important Point here
is it's not a button we are not selling
a button you cannot build a button you
push and then it does it automatically
and that's okay and that gets to those
three groups I mentioned you have the
academic Ivory Tower people I criticize
their approach on rag you have the
Enterprise Ivory Tower people some
people they don't want to try it until
it's a push button and they're gonna be
sitting there in their Ivory Tower
forever because there's amazing stuff
but it's not a push button and that's
okay if you can remove 96% of the work
that's one of the kind of customer
results we've seen from these migrations
that's amazing you should take that all
day every day and stop waiting for the
push button that's awesome so you
mentioned agents there we hear a lot of
the term agentic and it seems to mean
different things to to different folks
what does this world of agents and
agentic mean to you what do you have now
and how do you think about it going
forward I think an agent is anything
that automates software development that
takes away some of the rot tasks that's
what an agent is in everyday language I
don't hire an agent if I'm a basketball
player my agent doesn't shoot the
baskets for me it doesn't take over my
job it does the part of my job that I
hate doing as a basketball player to be
clear I am a coder I'm not a basketball
player but my agent I love the whole
basketball playing part I don't like the
whole signing contracts part that's what
an agent does it takes the stuff that
you hate doing there's a lot of gate
heating about agents and I think it's so
funny because ultimately I think that
the agents that actually have a real
impact that are working today those are
the ones that I think of their future
and we've got these customers that are
building these agents on our platform
there's so much more that we have coming
out to make that possible more apis and
this is this something that has really
accelerated over the last six to eight
months with customers just starting to
build these code migration agents these
code review agents these test generation
agents and the important thing is that
the agents that we see working today are
the ones that automate this repetitive
dumb process they're not the ones that
replace the human developer end to end
is not a moral thing I'm not saying oh
the people that try to replace human
devs or bad whatever I'm not making a
moral statement I'm saying those do not
work today and they will only work if
they can be built on a foundation where
you have a lot of these simpler real
agents that automate the more concrete
things like the things that we can do
today you can automate significant parts
of a codiv you can automate significant
parts of test generation and if you can
automate so much so that 80% or more of
the work is being done in a pretty
prescriptive way then I believe that an
endtoend agent that's actually trying to
write a new feature or fix any arbitrary
issue will actually have a much greater
rate of success because if you look at
where those things fail today a lot of
it is not actually doing the hard part A
lot of it is writing a good test that
meets my standards or these other things
you got to cify all of those those
frankly do not work and they will not
work until we see agents automating away
a lot of the more repetitive parts of
the development process so that's the
horizontal agent that is this task for
every developer in the company let's
take that away let's automate that the
vertical agents are the ones that try to
replace human developers end to end and
frankly those just don't work yet yeah
I've seen the same thing and again where
you see some of the demos where they
work where it's again give me a to-do
list at web app from scratch they're
good at that because yeah I you can one
shot that with some good B exactly
exactly yeah that's funny that's awesome
so one of the interesting things I see
in the Enterprise is the kind of change
from the early days where management was
like Over My Dead Body are you going to
do this AI stuff to my c-base to very
quickly oh my God we're not going to be
able to compete with our competition if
we don't start using these tools and
then trying to work out the calculating
the ROI of these tools and for me some
of the early metrics that people use
like completion rate were a little
comical to be honest like could tweak
the back end to do different things to
get very different completion results
and when I step back a lot of the time
it was more about not getting stuck as a
developer it's not like giving you the
perfect one offline of code it's like
when you don't get into the state of oh
my God what do I do from here as long as
I can keep pulling on a thread moving
forward as a developer and get my task
done like that's fine keep me in that W
I'm curious what you've seen around and
if you've seen enter is maturing a
little bit too here too on how they're
actually measuring all of these tools
how they're deciding when to use tools
how to use tools and what's been going
on there yeah it's changed so much and
we saw a lot of people as you said start
out where they say oh we're never going
to use this and then their concession
was we'll use it when it is as accurate
as a human developer and I love that
because then what do you think I ask
them I say okay how accurate is your
human developer and then they spit out
their coffee and they don't measure and
if they did measure it it would probably
be embarrassing so much of what we have
had to do is understand the psychology
of the Enterprise and in particular some
of the people in the Enterprise Ivory
Tower and how to get them to walk down
how to get them to understand this is
not a button that they push that is
perfect we're not claiming it is and
actually that's maybe not what they want
that there is something real today and
we've had a lot of customers that when
they were trying Source craft and a
bunch of other AI things they would um
run a quick test they'd get developers
to spend a day they maybe 10 developers
each of them would use a different tool
and they would try a bunch of
Representative tasks we loved when they
were actually hard and their existing
code bases and they would get to some of
the messiness that developers have and
they'd see how long did it take
developers to do that task on the
different tools they'd see the quality
of the code and then they do a
qualitative review of that code and we
won a ton of those that starts to get a
little bit more rigor and then a lot
more ways to measure you obviously have
some of the output metrics like what
percent of code is being written we
actually measure what percent of code is
being merged which is a nice higher bar
because it means that code has gone
through code review yeah but then
ultimately I think developers are
getting to a world where we can no
longer hide behind output metrics if you
take the point of view of an Enterprise
engineering leader or CEO of a big
company every other department other
than software engineering is asked to
basically report on some key metrics
like how much money did you make the
company how much money did you save the
company or how much risk did you reduce
and developers man we've gotten by for
so many years with oh we're working so
hard you can't measure us and developers
are paid way more than anyone else and
you have way more Developers for most of
the big Banks they have more people with
a job title sofware developer than any
other job title and I I think that is
going to change and that will change in
that developers are required to have
business impact because we can cut out
in the future a lot of the kind of
friction and we actually can get closer
to hey we built this product that
generated this amount of Revenue and
look developers are smart people we can
understand the business side we can go
work with customers the whole economy of
startups and people that were coders in
a dark room that can go to being amazing
sales people like it shows that being a
developer takes high IQ so we can do
those things and I love that because
that means basically the way to measure
developer impact is what is the business
business impact and with agents you get
so much closer to the actual business
impact with an agent you can take some
business problem like we need to come
into compliance with the EU digital
markets act on our codebase and that
means 10,000 changes and if we do that
it's going to save us$ 150 million doll
in fines from the EU and if you can make
an agent that can automate 95% of that
which we've got customers that have then
I would say that agent is worth $150
million and that is beautiful because it
gets us so much closer rather than oh
developer productivity and how do you
measure it yeah absolutely I I feel like
we've gotten enough of the path at times
when I don't know like working at Google
for example at times you'd see all of
these situations where people follow
incentives right not in a bad way it's
just the the natural course of humanity
and then you say oh there's a job ladder
that requires certain technical
complexity to get to the next level so
what's going to happen people are going
to build things that level of technical
complexity versus solving particular
business impact that in the most simple
way possible and everything else my
other favorite one was within the
Enterprise was once you got a product
like you have that's partially in the
IDE showing the customers how much
average time their developers were
actually writing
code was very eye openening to some I
remember some like saying like what what
do you assume it was and they're like
you know our developers work six days a
week and they're at least writing code
eight hours a day i' be like that's
interesting because the data we have for
your developers is one hour a day
writing code like you've got them in
meetings all day right you've got like
all of this other stuff and so being
able to like totally break open what
developers are actually doing and how
they're doing it I think that's so much
part of all of this revolution as well
yeah and that's a great example where
developers want to be coding more and so
you find where's there alignment between
developers and and managers I think that
maybe some developers have a fear that
more measurement of what they do is
going to be bad is but no actually it is
there's no CEO in the world who wants
their developers to be spending time in
meetings or doing grunt work and so once
you can shine a light on that I think
it's going to help everybody and by the
way when developers have more business
impact then they make more money totally
absolutely so Steve Yi on your team
wrote an interesting piece on the death
of the junior Dev which got a lot of
people very link baky kind of title to
begin with and then I think he just
updated it to be death of the stubborn
Dev can you explain a little bit the the
core premise to what he's talking about
there yeah Steve Yi on our team has been
incredible he was responsible for
building a lot of Google's internal code
search system that was an inspir ation
for us so it's amazing to have him on
our team now and he also came out with
this idea of chat oriented programming
which is among other things a way to
tell those people in the Enterprise
Ivory Tower that the job of developer is
changing and the point is not that AI is
going to do all the work the point is
that you need to have all your
developers treat it like a companion and
work through when it maybe gets
something wrong and you get familiar
with it he's talking to so many
developers out there so many customers
he's coding himself seeing how all this
stuff works and there's still a really
big disconnect that a lot of us who are
working in code AI feel with some
developers and I was just talking to a
friend who's at a company that is very
relatively AI forward and developer
forward but even in his company he
experiences so much AI skepticism from
other developers and it's this stuff
that you just do not understand how to
wrap your mind around it's developers
saying oh no AI can't do that and you
say you tried it they say no and then
you try to get them to sit down next to
you and say I'm going to do this and you
watch and you can see them like trying
to Riggle away from you like I've got
three-year-old and when I pick him up
sometimes he tries to rigle away and he
goes boneless you know it's like that
same feeling they do not want to see it
they do not want to know that AI can do
this and that stubbornness it is going
away fast but Stevie he wanted to go and
make it go away faster and we try all
kinds of different ways and sometimes
you got to be really blunt with these
people that the way that they think is
possible is no longer and stubborn
developers that's true and the junior
developer idea it's a mindset you can
have a junior developer who's 50 years
old you can have a junior developers
straight out of college turns out that
actually a lot of the youngest
developers are ones that have been using
the AI coding tools ever since they
started to code and have a leg up it's a
mindset you learn by doing you learn the
help of a this is not the kind of thing
where expectations be low the first five
years of your career the whole ramp has
changed in a good way and anyone with
high IQ and high drive is going to
thrive in this kind of world I think
that the message is being received and
the beautiful thing about this is AI is
so obviously transformational and
Powerful that as soon as someone changes
their mind and says hey this stuff is
actually pretty good you ask them hey
were you ever against Ai and they say oh
no I was always for it so this is gonna
be flash in the pan in two years from
now everyone's gonna be like oh yeah I
knew this was gonna be good all along
yeah that's so funny isn't it like I
sometimes have and still some Skeptics
who are just like ah it's just like this
I'm pairing with this really bad Junior
developer that doesn't know much and
it's okay let's say that it is a junior
developer it's a junior developer that
knows everything like every human
developer has jointed knowledge right I
could be an expert in this that's why I
hate the term Junior right and like
beginner versus so I could be an expert
in this technology and a beginner in in
that technology and so just that notion
and already seeing people that were I
told to developers who are in a monor
repo for their company where the back
end is all rust and they're a front end
developer in typescript and they never
touch the rust and now they touch the
rust like it's fine having that right
and then it turns out it's not that
Junior over developer obviously it's not
perfect to your point it's not just like
the one bud and it it does the thing it
doesn't understand all of your intent it
doesn't right like you have to work with
it you got to tell it stuff and this has
been with our prompt Library a big
unlock because in any given Enterprise
our job is to win over 100% of the devs
we can't say oh those 10% they're too
far gone if we don't do that then the
Enterprise customer is not very happy
and it turns out that if you can give
that last 10% of devs that are stubborn
you don't have them actually write a
prompt because frankly they're not good
at writing prompts that's part of the
problem you just have them click a
button to run a prompt that someone else
in their team made to generate a great
unit test or something like that then
they're like holy [ __ ] this actually
worked pretty well and then they can go
see what's the kind of prompt that I had
to write and so often when we would find
people saying hey this stuff didn't work
well we'd say what prompt are you using
and there they go boneless again but
once we got find out what the prompt
they were using it was obvious there was
one case with a very smart developer I
was at a customer site in the room big
projector up and he was walking through
some of his workflow and he said hey
this didn't work well and we were
helping him with stuff and basically he
wanted to summarize a really long CI
error log and his prompt to Source graph
was please explain this in detail and he
wrote that out and then he pasted it in
and he said the problem is that it's
like too damn long I just want to get a
summary of it and we're like What if you
just ask it to summarize he's like I did
and he tried summarize and it was still
a little bit too long it was like two
paragraphs long he's like this still way
too long what if you ask you to
summarize in 50 words or less and so he
did that and then it worked and that's
just some of the like handholding that
we have had to do but when you think
about why is everyone not using this
it's things like that and there's a lot
of blocking and tackling that's got to
happen for this whole Behavior to change
but we view it as hard job to help do
that I think Tesla does too yeah
absolutely yeah I think it's interesting
to see how much English is going to be
involved in building things right and it
already is we already use it in
requirement stocks and comments and this
and the other but now with chat and in
our world we deal a lot with
specifications and being able to Define
things that it becomes more about not
geeking out on like syntax in a
particular language of how to get
something done but it's more just how do
you break down problems and actually
think through what you're trying to
build and that's developing it's okay to
be doing less of the other stuff that
when you like step back it's like that's
I don't want to be spending time in that
toil like you were talking about at the
beginning yeah like it's okay it's safe
developers like there's still plenty to
be done yeah and it should be the higher
level more value driven uh impactful
things that that make sense anyway so
yeah super excited to see more and more
people get over that and to your point
of watching the people just coming into
the industry now the even with my kids
that are coding right like they've had
this from the beginning like kind of if
I was like oh actually we're gonna turn
that off and you have no access to that
it' be like you're insane right it' be
like you're gonna take away the syntax
highlighting too why would you do any of
this stuff right yeah I know one good
test is does a company when they're
hiring Engineers allow the engineers to
use AI
in the interview and I think the answer
should be absolutely yes absolutely no
that's really funny so as you think
about the future of code AI what are the
things that you think pretty clearly you
think is a solid understanding of this
is where things are going to change and
other areas that you still think are
very like up in the air that that you're
not sure of the thing that is really
concrete is we now have a road map for
iteratively automating more of the
software development process a lot of
these rote tasks we can build an agent
that can go and generate tests not with
100% accuracy but pretty good we can do
that for updating the change log for
cutting a release for creating a new UI
screen all these things and across an
Enterprise you just look at what are the
most common things developers are doing
and what can we automate and anything in
the intersection of both of those that's
something that we want our customers to
be able to build an agent to do and
there's a ton of work there's a lot of
stuff that we'll need to do in
particular to get that feedback loop to
see was that correct and if not then go
run it again and that could occupy us
and our customers for many more years to
come it's like turning software
development into a factory and by the
way when I say Factory that is a good
thing that is you no longer need to make
it by hand at home I'm not thinking
software developers are in the factory
I'm thinking Machinery is in the factory
and software developers get the nice
widget on the conveyor belt afterwards
so that's actually a good Vision I think
though what's unclear is
when the Holy Grail of replacing some
endtoend human developer tasks will
actually work well enough for the vast
majority development and the vast
majority development happens in the
Enterprise on a complex code basis that
makes [ __ ] tons of money and that can't
break and all of that and our vision is
that by stacking up a bunch of these
little micro automations these agents
that automate small parts of it that
we're going to be able to do that but I
think there's a lot of uncertainty I
think there's some competing Visions out
there that say
gp9 is GNA just dump out perfect code
that somehow does everything we need I
think that's fanciful thinking but this
is the Battleground and I'm really
excited that we get to work on this
every single day we're hiring by the way
any really smart folks that want to work
on this please join us reach out that's
the big Battleground and it's literally
the multi- trillion dollar question
that's awesome Quinn thank you so much
for taking the time to to chat through
these things I feel definitely very
aligned on what we've talked about today
too and it's really fun to think about
what's a word of when you've got AI like
my kids AI native from day one what does
development look like and how do we
iterate from here to there yeah there's
a few years of work for us to work on
and it's just super exciting to see this
to see this all change so thanks again
yeah absolutely thank you it's great to
chat again and to everyone who's
listening happy coding
[Music]
thanks for tuning in join us next time
on the AI native Dev brought to you by
Tesla